It's like, if I save it, I've learned it, right?
Does this sound familiar to you?
and then they just gather dust?
But here's the thing,
is that your note-taking app...
So these AI knowledge bases can't read the video content at all.
So, I decided to use AI myself to create a completely free plugin.
to solve this problem once and for all.
This plugin is called SABATCH.
Its core function is to batch-download subtitles from Bilibili videos.
You can even grab content directly from a user's homepage,
favorite lists, playlists, and so on.
Basically, it covers almost everything on Bilibili.
and feed it directly into your AI knowledge base.
This makes learning way more efficient than just mindlessly watching videos.
Nice.
Since the plugin comes with a lot of features,
So I've put together a super detailed, step-by-step guide for installation and use.
So, just finish watching the video, and you'll know where to get it.
Using the plugin is super straightforward.
Let me just show you how it works.
Once it's up and running,
First, we need to get a cookie from our Bilibili account.
So, we'll click on "Get Cookie".
Next, we need to select the type of content we want to fetch.
In this case, I'll just select 'Get Favorites'.
On the left here, I've got some videos about learning social media.
Alright, so first, I'm gonna click on 'Get Current URL'.
And then just click 'Get Videos', and you're good to go.
And just like that, look! I've successfully grabbed dozens of videos in an instant.
Next, we need to get their subtitles.
Then I just click on this 'Get Subtitles' button, and that's it.
See? The subtitles for all these videos have been successfully retrieved.
And for videos with multiple subtitles,
And in this section, we can also select the language we want.
It has Chinese,
English,
Japanese,
And here, we can choose which language types we want to export.
Before exporting,
We can also do some configuration.
For instance, let's talk about the export mode.
So, do we want to export all the subtitles into a single zip file,
or export each one as a separate file.
I'll just go ahead and select the ZIP compressed format.
Select the file naming format for the MD files.
So I'll just go with the first option, which is to import plain text.
We can also add the video's title and link to the top.
author, publish date, and so on.
So I'm just going to check all of them here.
This makes it easy to trace back the source later on.
Click 'Export'.
And just like that, all the subtitles are neatly organized.
Super convenient, right?
All the specific steps for the process I just demonstrated,
And there's another feature that a lot of people have been hyping up for a long time.
And that is, to transcribe videos that don't have any built-in subtitles.
For example, this video doesn't come with any subtitles.
After we click on 'Get Subtitle',
it will prompt you that there are no external subtitles.
So we can't get the subtitles.
So now, we can just go ahead and click on this.
the button for transcribing videos without subtitles.
This will then use our local speech-to-text model to transcribe the audio.
the subtitles
The overall transcription accuracy is around 95%.
So for an AI knowledge base, it's perfectly fine.
However, the transcription process will take a little while longer.
Plus, the transcription speed also depends on the specs of your local computer.
So, once we confirm and the transcription is done,
it'll automatically identify it.
the language that best matches the current video.
And since my video is in Chinese,
So, it automatically detects the subtitle language as Chinese.
And then we can go ahead and export the subtitles as usual.
And now, comes the best part—what you can do with all these video subtitles you've got.
and just toss them right into an AI knowledge base.
And then you can just start asking questions directly.
This is way more efficient than just watching videos.
So, to sum it all up,
If you ever need to extract subtitles from Bilibili videos,
then this plugin will be more than enough for you.
And the best part? It's completely free.
So, about the installation method I just mentioned...
I've already pinned it in the comments section.
So feel free to just go ahead and use it.
Honestly, it feels amazing.
And developing and fine-tuning this plugin took a ton of my time.
If you find this plugin useful,
and helps you save time,
Please give me a like,
and maybe give me a follow.
It really means a lot to me.
and that's what truly motivates me to keep updating the SABATCH plugin.
Alright, that's everything for this video.
I'm Burn.
Let's learn together and get stronger seven times over.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye!